CHRISTOPHER BOWMAN

Full Stack Developer - New London, CT | 508-302-9166

cbowman.se@gmail.com | github.com/cbowman422 | christopher-bowman.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/cbowman422 |

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer incorporating experience in software development, mathematics, and engineering, with a specialty in full stack JavaScript technologies and React.js. Organized and professional I have the experience to solve challenging problems and ask well developed questions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript | Python | SQL | Mongo | JSON | EJS | HTML5 | CSS | MATLAB

Databases - PostgreSQL | MongoDB

Libraries and Frameworks - React.js | Express.js | Django

Interpersonal Skills - Communicating Effectively | Working Collaboratively | Problem Solving

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

3/2023 - Present

Independent Consultant | Front End Engineer | (Remote)

Scott's Landscaping, Inc

- Rebuilt and maintained front end server with JavaScript and React.js framework.
- Responsible for front end development and design flow.

6/2020 - 11/2022

General Dynamics Electric Boat | Solid Mechanics Structural Engineer II | (Remote/ Hybrid)

- Simulated dynamic events for 2 Virginia and 1 Columbia class Submarines, using ABAQUS scripting (a Python object-oriented programming language).
- Analyzed Submarine models with Finite Element Method software ABAQUS/CAE and a Python based house code, supported in static and dynamic structural analysis .
- Obtained Secret level security clearance and was promoted to Structural Engineer II as a result of 4 above satisfactory reviews.

1/2019 - 12/2019

University of Massachusetts, Amherst | Teaching Assistant | (On Site)

- Supported two classes for "Theory- Modeling Principles and Applications in Finite Element Analysis" and "Machine Component Design", gaining leadership experience.
- Accurately graded over 300 mini projects of high technical difficulty.
- Hosted 2 and 3-hour, well attended, office hour sessions twice weekly for 14 weeks to help students with questions and projects.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

3/2023

Money Mania - MongoDB | Express | React.js | Node.js | HTML | CSS | JSON

Money Mania is a MERN application designed for students to learn about finance. For the GA 2023 Gamifying Hackathon and placing runner up. Worked on a team of 3 UX/UI designers and 4 software developers. Responsible for the backend server as well as 3 client pages.

2/2023

Millie's Messenger - Sockets.IO | MongoDB | Express | React.js | Node.js | HTML | CSS | JSON | JWT

Millie's Messenger is a MERN chat application designed to live chat with other users using Socket.IO. A user can login and send private messages to others, join a live chat room, and set a status.

12/2022

HAPI HOUR - React.js | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Grid | Flexbox | thecocktaildb.com

HAPI Hour is a front-end web application built to help users navigate recipes from the cocktaildb API. Users can search by name/phrase search engine, search by ingredient search engine, or start with a base ingredient choice and browse.

EDUCATION

2/2023

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive, Bootcamp

• Full stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, SQL queries, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

5/2020

University of Massachusetts, Amherst

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

• Coursework in Computer Science, Engineering Statistics, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations, Multivariable Calculus, Calculus.